<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>AerieCat</title>
        <link>https://aeriecat.space/</link>
        <description>AerieCat feed, mostly just interesting things</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>8 August 2023</lastBuildDate>
        <item>
            <title>Added user interaction! (moved hosts)</title>
            <link>https://aeriecat.space/#p/weblog</link>
            <pubDate>25 August 2023</pubDate>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[
                    Site is no longer static. This is a seemingly minor change that required me to do a whole lot of backend work. My site was hosted on github pages and thus had to be static, but this feature broke that so i had to go get some actual web hosting.<br>
    My site is now running on an Apache server so i can work with cool things like <i>php</i> and stuff. pls don't abuse!!! 
                                    ]]>
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Added a "quotewall" feature</title>
            <link>https://aeriecat.space/#p/weblog</link>
            <pubDate>22 August 2023</pubDate>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[
                    I wanted like a way to store my thoughts and get them out like a twitter thread or something, but without twitter or any opther social media. So, i made a little thought bar that loads them in from a JSON.
                ]]>
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Website design update</title>
            <link>https://aeriecat.space/#p/weblog</link>
            <pubDate>8 August 2023</pubDate>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[
                    <h3>Website made better</h3>
                    added some sidebars and made it scale better, added this feed to the left and not sure what i'll do with the left
                ]]>
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Creating a recipe database, except smol and just for me</title>
            <link>https://aeriecat.space/#recipes</link>
            <pubDate>29 June 2023</pubDate>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[
                    <h3>recipes page added</h3>
                    hello all 1 persons reading this, sorry for all the broken notifs you might have gotten recently, I kept changing links as i updated the .htaccess to make the urls look pretty. Anyways, I started to realize my dream of being a food blogger so i added recipes to my page. In reality i just needed somewhere to put them and easily be able to send them to my mom :p
                ]]>
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>A newtab page</title>
            <link>https://aeriecat.space/#b/Newtab-Page</link>
            <pubDate>6 June 2023</pubDate>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[
                    <h3>A Homepage for my Computer June 6th</h3>
                    I got mad at the Brave browser for the last time a few weeks ago because every time i opened a new tab it would advertise some crypto stuff to me. I use brave because my school's online stuff doesn't like Firefox and it was the first chromium based one that advertised any type of privacy stuff. I've been losing layers of my paranoia as i transition so m didn't look to much into them. A few times when i would open my browser it would advertise some crypto thing to me. First it's built in homepage left a lot to be desired, then it would advertise an exchange or some NFT stuff and eventually i had enough and decided to just make my own alternative.
                    <br>
                    <br>
                    At first i decided to just do a collection of links to sites i visit a lot. I added them all quite easily to an HTML page and set it as my new tab page with <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/custom-new-tab-url/mmjbdbjnoablegbkcklggeknkfcjkjia?hl=en">Custom Newtab URL</a> and left it at that, but then i realized that i was using some sites alot to do simple things that i could probably use an API to grab. so i started creating some scripts in JavaScript to add and format some other things onto the page. I had never used JavaScript before so i had to learn it really quickly, but once you know one programming language, you know most of them so it wasn't that hard. I added a clock and weather to the new tab and these are now features i use daily. 
                    <br> 
                    <br>
                    after using it for a while i realized i would write notes a lot in my book that i really needed localized on my computer. I would write things like features i want to add to the site and things i need to do the next day so next I added a notes feature to the lower section. I also added a feature using google's maps API that will tell me the traffic on the way to work so i know how much time i have in the morning but it's broken right now because of CORS. More features and updates to come!
                    <h3>Image as of June 6</h3>
                    <img src="b/blog-images/newtab.png" width="700px" border="1">
                ]]>
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Exploring the Internets</title>
            <link>https://aeriecat.space/#b/exploring-the-internets</link>
            <pubDate>21 May 2023</pubDate>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[
                    <h3>exploring the internets</h3>
                    A hobby of mine that i recently picked up is exploring the internet. Not from a search engine, but simply clicking through links on sites and seeing where they go. I realize this isn't really a new thing, or something unique to me and that this was how the internet was used in the beginning. However, it does evoke a happy feeling to see sites that don't look corporate or extremely flashy, to see something that was hand made, typed without a guide, and probably really messy on the backend. 
                    <br> <br>
                    doing this you find sites that are regularly updated, sites that haven't been updated since the late 90s, archives of things you didn't know existed, and personal projects that people poured their heart and soul into that haven't had more than a few hundred visitors. You're exposed to ramblings of people who are probably insane and new ideas that you'd never heard of. 
                    <br> <br>
                    My explorations were what inspired me to work on this site, and in doing so made me a lot more aware of how the internet works
                    <h3>how to explore</h3>
                    exploration is easy, you find a link, go there, and look for more!
                    some things to look out for are buttons and banners.
                    Buttons are usually around 88x31 pixels and are made to show allegiances and connect other sites together. They can also be used to show things about the website or the site developer. Here's one for example:
                    <p><img src="/88x31/aeriecat.space.png"></p>
                    Banners are used more as an advertisement. example:
                    <p><img src="/banners/Aeriessite.png"></p>
                    another thing to look for is a webring, these are sites that all link each other together. these can make it easier to find new sites as they will usually have a list of sites or easy links to get between them all.
                    <h3>where to start</h3>
                    if i find a site i find interesting or one that has easy code to put a button on my page I'll put it in my <a href="../index#ExternalLinks" target="_parent">link list</a> page under 'cool sites i stumble upon'. There's also some helpfull lists on sizeof.cat at <a href="https://sizeof.cat/post/website-discovery/" target="_blank">this post</a>.
                ]]>
            </description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>